in this animation
we want to show the human
immune system with images never seen before
we will learn how macrophages as well as
other cells and mechanisms
protect our organism from death every day
our skin
like the bulk of a tree represents valuable Protection
however
the skin is also home to countless microorganisms
among other things
they are nourished and protected by an
oily fluid called sebum
sebum is produced by sebacious glands
sebum also contains antimicrobial elements
that can kill microbes
if they are harmful or too many microbes on the skin
the sebum is composed in such a way
that these microbes are killed
this creates a harmonious coexistence between
skin cells and microbes
a kind of symbiosis
these myocropes also keep one another in balance
and kill pathogens that can be dangerous to our cells
the protective layer of hollow organs such as nose
mouth and trachea
is a mucous membrane
mucus membranes possess Celia
Celia move back and forth in a wave like manner
this allows them to move mucus
to which foreign substances adhere
upward into the oral cavity
if you
concilier clearance is not sufficient
and tamp
is made to achieve clearance of unwanted particles
through cuffing
this is done by inhalation
followed by a sudden exhalation
so that
foreign substances are removed from the lungs and
trachea
the bone mirror has stem cells
it is the birth place for many different immune cells
which we also call lucocytes
stem cells divided to form daughter cells
asymmetric or symmetric
symmetric cell division results in
either two stem cells or two progenitor cells
as seen here
the progenitor cells divide again and again
thus a single stem cell becomes many immune cells or
leukocides
a common immune cell is the neutrophil
some of the neutrophils remain in the bone merrow
while others make their way into the bloodstream
our neutrophyll belongs to the so called innate
immune system
and moves through the blood vessels
during informatory processes
the endothelial cells of the blood vessels have
special receptors
thus initially there is weak adhesion than
strong adhesion
and finally
the granulocyte goes through the endothelium
this process is called diapedesis
the path
through the connective tissue has already been made by
other neutrophylls
our neutrophyll only has to follow cycchines
that is signal substances of other cells
a process called Chemo Texas
there they are bacteria everywhere
they produce toxins and this
harm the cells of the organism
a neutrophil's job is to eat these bacteria
this eating process is called phagocytosis
in addition some of the neutralfuls produce
certain cytochines that attract other granulocides
cells of the innate immune system or macrophages
they arrive on the scene before neutrophils
fagazytose bacteria and produce a signal substance
tumor necrosis vector
it suppresses the feeling of hunger causes fever
stimulates leukocyte production
another leukocyte type is the t cell
t cells possess receptors
what do they need them for
microphages or professional antigen presenting cells
they have the ability to present antigens via
certain proteins on their surface
and this initiates certain processes
some t cells can use
their receptors to recognize exactly those
antigens of the macrophages
for which they have been trained
in the thymes
let us take a closer look at this
t cells are also formed in the bone marrow
they then migrate via the bloodstream to the thymus
good they mature on the thymus
they are called t for thymus cells
in the thymus
which is one of the primary lymphoid organs
t cells form antigen receptors
afterwards
they usually migrate two secondary lymphoid organs
such as the lymph notes and the spleen
on the lymphoid organs
naive t cells and endritic cells meet
the endritic cells have already
had contact with a pathogen
and present the antigen on the surface
they are also professional antigen presenting cells
the t cell
scans the endritic cell for the antigen for which
the t cell was trained
in the thymus
if it finds the antigen
diesel activation begins and among other things
colonal expansion occurs
this cell reproduces itself thousands of times
these cells respond to a specific pathogen or antigen
then
some t cells stored their journey and migrate to other
tissues once there
the cytotoxic t cells scan other
cells with their receptors to look for cells
that have the specific antigen on the surface
if they find their antigen in a cell
they know that a pathogen for example is in the cell
the cytotoxic t cells begin to induce apoptosis
the cells debris are eventually eaten by mecrophagesis
and new cells form
there are not only cytotoxic t cells but others as well
tea helper cells
memory t cells regulatory t cells and others
t helper cells work hand in hand with B cells
b cells possess receptors like t cells
like t cells b cells also originate in the bone marrow
they then search for their specific antigen in the
lymphetic system
or in the bloodstream
if the B cell finds its antigen with its receptors
either activation occurs immediately
or the B cell moves into the lymphoid tissue where
t haper cells wait
teahubber cells as we have seen before
we're also trained for one specific antigen
for this reason
the B cell presents its antigen on the surface
this allows the t cell
with its receptors to scan the B cell
what is the antigen
for which the t cell has been trained
it gives the starting signal for the division
and maturation
of the B cell
as with t cells colonal expansion occurs
thus thousands of new B cells or plasma blasts
and plasma cells are generated from a single B cell
memory b cells are also produced
which will spring into action in the event of another
subsequent infection
during acute infection
plasma blasts and plasma cells
immediately begin to produce antibodies
and they release these antibodies into the bloodstream
antibodies are also often called immunoglobulence
at the toxin the bacterium the antigen is in the blood
the antibody just produced by the plasma
cell combined to it
in this way for example
a toxin can be rendered harmless
and an antigen can be mocked so that
macrophages can recognize it more
easily and fagurtize it more quickly
this process is called obsonization
all immune cells have as stem cell as their origin
it develops into progenitor
cells and eventually into the immune cells
just tune
other important immune cells on natural killer cells
and platelets
platelets also known as thrombusites
originate in the bone marrow from mega carriocytes
mega carriocytes have pseudopodia that extend
into blood vessels of the bone merrow
it is through these pseudopodia
that platelets are emitted into circulation
one mega carrier side
can produce 1000 to 3000 platelets
this process is called thrombopoesis
the platelets move through the blood
vessels of the body
injury to your blood vessel occurs
hemostasis begins
the platelets adhere first
to the collagen fibers of the connective tissue
and eventually adhere to one another
this results in a quiet fretch ire platelet plug
which prevents the blood from escaping
eventually fiber and strands form on the platelets
which ensures a stronger plug
and it will bind more platelets and red blood cells
thus a strong clot is formed